為什麼今天來
Why today?
你想聽我說出來
Do you want to hear me say it?
距你上次約診已經過了一年半
18 months since our last appointment.
你看報的吧
You read the papers?
有時看
Sometimes...
你也看電視吧
And you watch telly?
你知道我為什麼來
You know why I'm here.
我來是因為...
I'm here because...
發生了什麼  約翰
What happened, John?
夏...
Sherl...
你得說出來
You need to get it out.
我最好的朋友...
My best friend...
夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Sherlock Holmes...
死了
is dead.
新福爾摩斯 第2季 第3集
Sherlock S02E03 720p hdtv x264
萊辛巴赫瀑布
Falls Of The Reichenbach.
萊辛巴赫隕落
特納[英畫家]的傑作
Turner's masterpiece.
幸得尋回
Thankfully recovered,
多虧了絕世奇才夏洛克·福爾摩斯先生
owing to the prodigious talent of Mr Sherlock Holmes.
三個月前
這份小禮物代表了我們的謝意
A small token of our gratitude.
鑽石袖扣  我的襯衫袖口都有扣子了
Diamond cufflinks... All my cuffs have buttons.
他是說謝謝
He means thank you.
- 我說了嗎  - 快說
- Do I?  - Just say it.
- 謝謝  - 等等
- Thank you.  - Hang on.
萊辛巴赫英雄
業餘偵探尋回特納傑作
蘇格蘭場因遺漏線索而出醜
銀行業巨頭遭綁架
終於能和家人團聚
Back together with my family,
在恐怖的劫難過後
after my terrifying ordeal.
我要感謝這位幫我逃過一劫的人...
And we have one person to thank for my deliverance...
夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
領帶夾  我從不戴領帶
Tie pin. I don't wear ties.
萊辛巴赫英雄解救被綁人質
瑞科萊蒂漏網逃脫
彼得·瑞科萊蒂  自1982年起就佔據了
Peter Ricoletti... Number one on Interpol's
國際刑警通緝名單榜首
most wanted list since 1982.
我們抓住了他  我們必須感謝
Well, We got him, and there's one person
這位為我們提供了決定性線索的人
we have to thank for giving us the decisive leads.
多虧了他慣用的那些手腕和才智
With all his customary diplomacy and tact.
- 反話  - 可不是
- Sarcasm.  - Yes.
我們都出錢了
We all chipped in.
把帽子戴上  把帽子戴上
Put the hat on. Put the hat on.
對  夏洛克  戴上吧
Yes, Sherlock, put it on.
湊合應付一下吧
Just get it over with.
每日明星快訊
全球獨家
技術專家夏洛克再解難題
技術英雄破懸案
技術專家
"Boffin!"
技術專家夏洛克·福爾摩斯
"Boffin Sherlock Holmes!"
每人都得有一個
Everybody gets one.
- 一個什麼  - 小報綽號
- One what?  - Tabloid nickname.
蘇珊大媽  陰險尼克[真人秀名人]
SuBo, Nasty Nick.
也許很快我也會有一個
I'll probably get one soon.
第五頁  第六欄  第一句
Page five, column six, first sentence.
為什麼非要登戴帽子的照片
Why is it always the hat photograph?!
- 單身漢約翰·華生  - 這算什麼帽子
- "Bachelor John Watson. "  - What kind of hat is it?
單身漢  他們到底在暗示什麼
"Bachelor" What the hell are they implying?!
這算帽子嗎  為什麼兩邊都有檐
Is it a cap? Why has it got two fronts?
這是獵鹿帽
It's a deerstalker.
他身邊通常都有
"Frequently seen in the company of
- 單身漢約翰·華生  - 用這帽子獵鹿
- bachelor John Watson ".  - Stalk deer with the hat.
怎麼用  扔著玩
" What are you going to do, throw it?
已證實約翰·華生是單身漢
"Confirmed bachelor John Watson."
- 獵殺飛盤  - 這太過分了
- A death frisbee!  - This is too much,
- 我們得小心點了  - 上面還有垂檐
- we need to be more careful.  - It's got flaps.
遮耳垂檐  這是遮耳帽  約翰
Ear flaps, it's an ear hat, John.
你說小心點是什麼意思
What do you mean, more careful?
我是說  這已經不是獵鹿帽了
I mean, this isn't a deerstalker now,
這是夏洛克·福爾摩斯的帽子
it's a Sherlock Holmes hat.
也就是說  你不再是個私家偵探了
I mean, you're not exactly a private detective any more.
- 你就快成名人了  - 會過去的
- You're this far from famous.  - It'll pass.
最好能過去  媒體風向會變  夏洛克
It better pass. The press will turn, Sherlock,
他們總變來變去  他們會轉過來針對你
they always turn and they'll turn on you.
- 你真的這麼在意  - 什麼
- It really bothers you.  - What?
- 人們的看法  - 是的
- What people say.  - Yes.
是對我的看法  我不懂為什麼你會心煩
About me? I don't understand. Why would it upset you?
你盡量保持低調就對了
Just try to keep a low profile.
這周找點小案子吧
Find yourself a little case this week.
別再上新聞
Stay out of the news.
倫敦塔
皇冠權杖
你電話響了
That's your phone.
一直響個沒完
It keeps doing that.
那個  你跟他長談過了嗎
So, did you just talk to him for a really long time?
亨利·費什加沒有自殺
Henry Fishguard never committed suicide.
那些倫敦警探什麼都看不出來
Bow Street runners missed everything.
這案子挺急的吧
Pressing case, is it?
沒解決的案子都急
They're all pressing until they're solved.
請收好您的鑰匙  謝謝
Put your key back please. Thank you.
抱歉  先生
Excuse me, sir.
有金屬物品嗎  鑰匙  手機
Any metal objects, keys, mobile phones?
你可以通過了
You can go through.
謝謝
Thank you.
要來杯茶嗎  兄弟
Fancy a cuppa then, mate?
好啊  當然了
Yeah, why not?
國債收益為七
Gilts at seven.
荷蘭電信暴跌  謝謝  哈維
Dutch Telecoms in free- fall. Thank you, Harvey.
英格蘭銀行
本頓維爾監獄
你說什麼
What are you saying?
拒絕所有假釋申請  並恢復死刑
Refuse them all parole and bring back the rope?
開始吧
Let's begin.
緊急情況  請離開
This is an emergency. Please leave.
先生  我必須請您離開
Sir, I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
長官  有非法闖入案件
Sir, there's been a break- in.
不在我們的職責範圍
Not our division.
你肯定不想放過
You'll want it.
金庫
The vault!
金庫開啟
居然黑了倫敦塔安保系統  怎麼可能
Hacked into the Tower of bloody London's security?! How?!
就說我們馬上來了
Tell them we're on our way!
又有一起  還是非法闖入
There's been another one, another break- in.
英格蘭銀行
Bank of England!
長官  安保系統壞了  失靈了
Sir! Security's down, sir. It's failing.
現在什麼情況
What is it now?
本頓維爾監獄
Pentonville Prison.
不是吧
No!
不著急
No rush.
我來看看吧
I'll get it, shall I?
- 給你  - 現在沒空  忙
- Here.  - Not now, I'm busy.
- 夏洛克  - 沒空
- Sherlock...  - Not now!
他回來了
He's back.
來倫敦塔玩吧
金·莫堥蒂
那玻璃比什麼都堅硬
That glass is tougher than anything.
但比不上碳晶體  他用的是鑽石
Not tougher than crystallised carbon. He used a diamond.
去找夏洛克
世紀大案
國會質疑為何倫敦塔  本頓維爾監獄  英格蘭銀行會同時遭到入侵
且罪犯為同一人  金姆斯·莫堥蒂
犯罪主腦莫堥蒂在罪案現場
用"去找夏洛克"字樣塗鴉諷刺福爾摩斯
該案件引起廣泛國際關注
業餘偵探成為專家證人
- 準備好了  - 好了
- Ready?  - Yes.
- 福爾摩斯先生  - 退後  退後
- Mr Holmes. Mr Holmes.  - Stand back. Stand back.
- 讓他們過去  - 謝謝
- Let them through.  - Thank you.
上車
Get in.
- 記住...  - 知道
- Remember...  - Yes.
- 記住...  - 知道了
記住他們告訴你的話
Remember what they told you.
- 別耍小聰明  - 不要
- Don't try to be clever.  - No.
拜託你  簡單明瞭好不好
Please, just keep it simple and brief.
難道上庭的明星證人就不能才智超群嗎
God forbid the star witness at the trial should come across intelligent.
才智可以  你那天才欠揍性格就免了
Intelligent, fine. Let's give "Smart- arse" a wide berth.
- 我該怎樣還怎樣  - 你有沒有聽我說
- I'll just be myself.  - Are you listening to me
就在今天  在貝利老街外
Today, outside the Old Bailey...
這場審判是世紀...
This is the trial of the century...
對金姆斯·莫堥蒂的審判...
The trial of James Moriarty...
金姆斯·莫堥蒂今天早些時候被指控...
James Moriarty, earlier today accused of...
企圖盜竊王冠權杖
attempting to steal the Crown Jewels.
在貝利老街我們將見到
At the Old Bailey we have
萊辛巴赫英雄夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Reichenbach hero Sherlock Holmes...
你介意把手伸到我的口袋媔
Would you mind slipping your hand into my pocket?
謝謝
Thanks.
莫堥蒂王冠偷竊案
Crown Moriarty,
請前往第10法庭
please proceed to Court 10.
是你
You're him.
心水夏洛克
進錯廁所了你
Wrong toilet.
- 我是你的超級粉絲  - 顯而易見
- I'm a big fan.  - Evidently.
我讀了你那些案子  一直在追
I read your cases, follow them all.
在我襯衫上簽個名好嗎
Sign my shirt, would you?
我的粉絲分兩種
There are two types of fans.
有本事在下次謀殺前抓住我  這是第一種
Catch me before I kill again, Type A.
- 第二種呢  - 搭個出租就到我家了
- What's Type B?  - Your bedroom's just a taxi ride away.
你猜我是哪種
Guess which one I am?
壓痕
口袋
墨水
- 都不是  - 是嗎
- Neither.  - Really?
你根本不是粉絲
No, you're not a fan at all.
你前臂上的壓痕  是在桌子邊緣壓的
Those marks on your forearm, edge of a desk.
你應該很匆忙地打了字
You've been typing in a hurry, probably,
截稿時間到了  壓力巨大
pressure on, facing a deadline.
就這些
That all?
你的手腕上有墨跡
There's a smudge of ink on your wrist,
上衣口袋鼓起
a bulge in your left jacket pocket.
- 有點露餡了  - 那污點是故意弄的
- Bit of a giveaway?  - The smudge is deliberate,
你想看看我是不是像別人說的那麼厲害
to see if I'm as good as they say I am.
油墨  報紙印刷用的
Oil- based, used in newspaper print.
不過是用食指塗抹的  你的手指
But drawn on with an index finger, your finger.
作為記者  你不太可能在報社沾到油墨
Journalist. Unlikely you get your hands dirty at the press.
你抹在那堿O試探我
You put that there to test me.
我開始喜歡你了
I'm liking you.
我替你想好標題了
you may like a great feature,
夏洛克·福爾摩斯  帽檐下的真相
"Sherlock Holmes, the man beneath the hat".
姬蒂
Kitty...
萊利  很高興見到你
Riley. Pleased to meet you.
不  我還是幫你免了這一問吧
Nah, I'm just saving you the job of asking.
不  我不接受採訪
No, I won't give you an interview.
不  我也不需要錢
No, I don't want the money.
你和約翰·華生只是精神伴侶嗎
You and John Watson, just platonic?
我能否在這個問題上也記下個不字
Can I put you down for a "No" there as well
新聞界有你們各種各樣的緋聞
There's all sorts of gossip in the press about you.
遲早你會需要個和你同一戰線的人
Sooner or later, you're going to need someone on your side.
一個幫你澄清流言的人
Someone to set the record straight.
你以為你能完成這種工作嗎
You think you're the girl for that job, do you?
我很聰明  你可以信任我
I'm smart and you can trust me...
完全信任
totally.
聰明  好吧  調查型記者
Smart? OK, investigative journalist.
很好  看著我說出你看到什麼
Good. Well, look at me and tell me what you see.
如果你能力出眾  你根本不需要採訪
If you're that skilful, you don't need an interview,
你可以直接讀到你要的一切
you can just read what you need.
做不到嗎  還是我來吧
No? OK, my turn.
我看你在尋找職業生涯第一份獨家新聞
I look at you and I see someone who's still waiting for their first big scoop,
以得到編輯的關注
so their editor will notice them.
你穿了條昂貴的短裙
You're wearing an expensive skirt,
還改過兩次裙邊
that's been rehemmed twice.
這是你僅有的高檔裙子
Only posh skirt you've got.
你的指甲  你沒錢經常保養
Your nails, you can't afford to do them that often.
我看到了一個慾望強烈的人
I see someone who's hungry,
我看到的不是聰明  當然更不是可靠
I don't see smart. I definitely don't see trustworthy.
我給你句引語吧  五個字
I'll give you a quote. If you like. Three little words.
你叫我噁心
You repel me.
- 犯罪顧問  - 是的
- "A consulting criminal."  - Yes.
你能詳細解釋一下證詞嗎
Your words. Can you expand on that answer?
金姆斯·莫堥蒂受人僱傭
James Moriarty is for hire.
- 他是個商人  - 是的
- A tradesman?  - Yes.
但不是幫你修暖氣那種服務
But not the sort who'd fix your heating?
不  是幫你裝炸彈或策劃暗殺那種
No, the sort who'd plant a bomb or stage an assassination.
不過我猜讓他修鍋爐也能幹得不錯
But I'm sure he'd make a decent job of your boiler.
你是否會將他描述為...
Would you describe him as...
- 引導  - 什麼
- Leading.  - What?
這樣不行  你這是引導證人
Can't do that.  You're leading the witness.
他會反對  而法官會支持
He'll object and the judge'll uphold.
福爾摩斯先生
Mr Holmes.
問我怎麼看  問我如何描述他
Ask me how, how would I describe him?
我對他有怎樣的看法  他們沒教過你嗎
What opinion have I formed of him? They don't teach you this?
福爾摩斯先生  沒有你幫忙法庭照樣轉
Mr Holmes, we are fine without your help.
你如何描述這個人  他的性格如何
How would you describe this man, his character?
錯誤一
First mistake.
金姆斯·莫堥蒂根本不是個人
James Moriarty isn't a man at all.
他是只蜘蛛
He's a spider.
網中心的蜘蛛
A spider at the centre of a web,
這張犯罪網中有上千條線
a criminal web with a thousand threads
而他對每一條的運作
and he knows precisely
都瞭如指掌
how each and every single one of them dances.
- 那你們認識...  - 不  別問這問題
- And how long...? - No, no. Don't, don't do that.
- 這問題爛透了  - 福爾摩斯先生
- That's really not a good question. - Mr Holmes!
我認識他多久了  問得真不怎麼樣
How long have I known him? Not your best line of enquiry.
見過兩次  總共五分鐘
We met twice, five minutes in total.
我拿槍指著他  他想炸死我
I pulled a gun, he tried to blow me up.
好像我倆挺來電
I felt we had a special something.
索雷爾律師  你真覺得這人是個專家麼
Miss Sorrel, are you seriously claiming this man is an expert?
他和被告就見過五分鐘
After knowing the accused for just five minutes?
兩分鐘我就能看透一個人  五分鐘夠充裕了
Two minutes would have made me an expert, five was ample.
- 福爾摩斯先生  那由陪審團決定  - 是嘛
- Mr Holmes, that's a matter for the jury. - Really?
商人
老師
有外遇
已婚
圖書管理員
一個圖書管理員  兩個老師
One librarian, two teachers,
兩人工作壓力很大  應該是金融人士
two high- pressure jobs, probably the City.
陪審團主席是醫療秘書  外國受訓
The foreman's a medical secretary, trained abroad,
- 因為她的速記  - 福爾摩斯先生
- judging by her shorthand. - Mr Holmes?
七個已婚  兩個在和對方搞外遇
Seven are married, two are having an affair with each other.
他們剛用完下午茶
They've just had tea and biscuits.
你想知道誰吃了威化餅麼
Would you like to know who ate the wafer?
福爾摩斯先生
Mr Holmes!
傳喚你來是為了回答索雷爾律師的問題
You've been called here to answer Miss Sorrel's questions,
不是讓你來展示自己有多聰明
not to give us a display of your intellectual prowess.
請言簡意賅地回答問題
Keep your answers brief and to the point.
否則就算你蔑視法庭
Anything else will be treated as contempt.
少顯擺一會你能死麼
Do you think you could survive for just a few minutes with out showing off!
我說什麼來著  讓你別耍小聰明
What did I say? I said don't get clever.
我又不是水龍頭說關就關
I can't just turn it on and off like a tap.
- 如何  - 什麼如何
- Well? - Well, what?
你不是一直在麼
You were there for the whole thing,
從頭到尾都在旁聽
up in the gallery, start to finish.
跟你說的一樣
Like you said it would be...
他靠著椅背  一直很淡定
sat on his backside, never even stirred.
莫堥蒂根本不打算為自己辯護
Moriarty is not mounting any defence.
英格蘭銀行  倫敦塔  本頓維爾監獄
Bank of England, Tower of London, Pentonville.
全國最安全的三個地方
Three of the most secure places in the country
六周以前  莫堥蒂成功闖入
and six weeks ago, Moriarty breaks in,
沒人知道手法  或者原因
no- one knows how or why.
- 我們只知道...  - 他被拘留了
- All we know is... - He ended up in custody.
- 別這樣  - 哪樣
- Don't do that. - Do what?
- 那表情  - 啥  - 你又露出那表情了
- The look. - Look? - You're doing the look again.
我自己又看不見
Well, I can't see it, can I?
我的臉啊
It's my face.
對  而且你露出了一種
Yes and it's doing a thing, you are doing
"我們都知道到底怎麼回事"的表情
"We both know what's really going on here" face.
- 確實嘛  - 我就不知道  所以我才討厭你那表情
- We do. - No, I don't, which is why I find the face so annoying.
如果莫堥蒂想要王冠  他可以直接拿走
If Moriarty wanted the jewels, he'd have them.
他想放走犯人  他們早就出獄了
If he wanted the prisoners freed, they'd be out on the streets.
他之所以現在還在監獄
The only reason he's still in a prison cell right now
是因為他想要被關起來
is because he chose to be there.
這是他計劃的一部分
Somehow this is part of his scheme.
克雷西爾律師  請把第一位證人傳上法庭
Mr Crayhill, can we have your first witness?
法官大人  我們沒有證人
Your Honour, we're not calling any witnesses.
我不懂
I don't follow.
你們不是辯方麼
You've entered a plea of not guilty.
可我的當事人並未提供任何證據
Nevertheless, my client is offering no evidence.
被告陳述完畢
The defence... rests.
陪審團的各位
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
金姆斯·莫堥蒂被控告
James Moriarty stands accused...
和多起盜竊未遂案有關
of several counts of attempted burglary.
若他罪名成立
Crimes which, if he's found guilty,
將被監禁多年
will elicit a very long custodial sentence,
可是  他的法律團隊
and yet... his legal team...
卻不提供任何證據
has chosen to offer no evidence
來為他進行辯護
whatsoever to support their plea.
這不尋常  但出於公正
I find myself in the unusual position
我給陪審團一個裁決建議
of recommending a verdict wholeheartedly.
你們必須判他有罪
You must find him guilty.
有罪
Guilty.
你們必須判他有罪
You must find him guilty.
開庭了
They're coming back.
才六分鐘
That's six minutes.
說實話居然用了這麼久
Surprised it took them that long, to be honest.
廁所排隊的人真多
There's a queue for the loo!
請陪審團宣佈你們一致通過的裁決
Have you reached a verdict on which you all agree?
罪名不成立  他們居然判他無罪
Not guilty, they found him not guilty.
沒有辯護  莫堥蒂無罪釋放
No defence and Moriarty's walked free.
夏洛克
Sherlock?
你在聽嗎  他出來了
Are you listening? He's out,
你知道他會找上你  夏...
you know he'll be coming after you. Sherl...
一般人會先敲門
Most people knock.
不過我想你也不是一般人
But then, you're not most people, I suppose.
水正好開了
Kettle's just boiled.
巴赫都都會震驚的
Johann Sebastian would be appalled.
- 能坐嗎  - 請
- May I? - Please.
你知道嗎  巴赫臨死之前
You know when he was on his deathbed, Bach,
聽見自己兒子在彈奏他的作品
he heard his son at the piano playing one of his... pieces.
還沒彈完男孩就不彈了
The boy stopped before he got to the end.
那個彌留之人就跳下床
The dying man jumped out of bed,
跑到鋼琴邊彈完了整首曲子
ran to the piano and finished it.
無法忍受未完成的樂章
Couldn't cope with an unfinished melody.
你也是  所以你才過來
Neither can you, that's why you've come.
實話說  你有那麼點開心
Be honest, you're a tiny bit pleased.
什麼  審判結果麼
What, with the verdict?
我又回來興風作浪了
With me, back on the streets.
每個童話故事都要有個老派的壞蛋
Every fairy tale needs a good old- fashioned villain.
你需要我  否則你屁都不是
You need me or you're nothing.
因為我們本來就很像
Because we're just alike, you and I,
只是你比我無聊
except you're boring.
你站在正義那一方
You're on the side of the angels.
當然  你控制了陪審團
You got to the jury, of course.
我都能闖入倫敦塔
I got into the Tower of London,
12間酒店房間又算什麼
you think I can't worm my way into 12 hotel rooms?
有線網
Cable network.
每個房間都有私人電視屏幕
Every hotel bedroom has a personalised TV screen.
每個人都有自己的弱點
And every person has their pressure point.
如果你想讓你可愛的孩子們安然無恙
就照我說的做
都有自己想保護的人
Someone that they want to protect from harm.
小菜一碟
Easy peasy.
你打算怎麼做
So how are you going to do it?
毀了我
Burn me?
就是這謎題  最後的謎題
That's the problem, the final problem.
你想到是什麼了嗎
Have you worked out what it is yet?
最後一案到底是什麼
What's the final problem?
我告訴過你  不過你仔細聽了嗎
I did tell you... but did you listen?
對你來說  說句"我不知道"有多困難
How hard do you find it, having to say "I don't know"?
- 我不知道  - 很聰明啊  真聰明
- I don't know. - That's clever, very clever, awfully clever.
說起聰明  你跟你那些小朋友說了嗎
Speaking of clever, have you told your little friends yet?
說什麼
Told them what?
- 為何我闖入那些地方卻空手而回  - 沒有
- Why I broke into all those places and never took anything? - No.
- 但你明白  - 當然
- But you understand? - Obviously.
那請說吧
Off you go, then.
你自己也知道  我還說什麼
You want me to tell you what you already know?
不  我要你證明你知道
No, I want you to prove that you know it.
- 什麼都不拿是因為你不需要  - 好
- You didn't take anything because you don't need to. - Good.
你再也不用拿任何東西了
You'll never need to take anything ever again.
很好  因為什麼
Very good, because?
因為英格蘭銀行  倫敦塔和本頓維爾監獄
Because nothing in the Bank of England, the Tower of London
堶惆S有東西能比上你手堥滬
or Pentonville Prison could possibly match the value of the key
能讓你闖入其中的鑰匙
that could get you into all three.
任何地方的任何門我都打得開
I can open any door anywhere
只要幾行計算機代碼就行
with a few tiny lines of computer code.
什麼私人銀行賬戶都是胡扯  全屬於我
No such thing as a private bank account now, they're all mine.
已經沒有秘密了  我掌控著秘密
No such thing as secrecy, I own secrecy.
核武器編碼
Nuclear codes?
我隨隨便便就能炸了北約
I could blow up NATO in alphabetical order.
滿世界都是封鎖的房間  有鑰匙便是國王
In a world of locked rooms, the man with the key is king.
親愛的  你真該看看我戴王冠的樣子
And honey, you should see me in a crown.
你是利用審訊宣傳自己
You were advertising all through the trial,
給世人展現你的能耐
you were showing the world what you can do.
你也幫了我
And you were helping.
客戶可多了  自由政府  情報組織
Big client list... rogue governments, intelligence communities,
恐怖組織
terrorist cells.
他們都想要我
They all want me.
轉眼我就成了萬人迷
Suddenly, I'm Mr Sex.
如果你能進入任何銀行
If you can break any bank,
你還在乎什麼最高價競買人
what do you care about the highest bidder?
我不在乎  我就是愛看他們搶破頭的樣
I don't, I just like to watch them all competing.
"爸爸最愛的是我"  凡人真可愛
"Daddy loves me the best." Aren't ordinary people adorable?
反正你有約翰了
Well, you know, you've got John.
我也該找個同居男友才對
I should get myself a live- in one.
- 你為什麼要這麼做  - 肯定很有趣
- Why are you doing all of this? - It must be so funny.
你並不真的想要金錢或權力
You don't want money or power, not really.
到底為了什麼
What is it all for?
我想解決那個問題
I want to solve the problem.
我們的問題
Our problem.
最後的謎題
The final problem.
就要開始了  夏洛克  墜落
It's going to start very soon, Sherlock... the fall.
fall[墜落]同有瀑布之意  在這娷驨
不過別怕  墜落跟飛翔一樣
But don't be scared, falling is just like flying,
不過下場只有死亡而已
except there's a more permanent destination.
我不喜歡謎語
Never liked riddles.
學著喜歡
Learn to.
因為我欠你一次墜落  夏洛克
Because I owe you a fall, Sherlock.
我  欠  你
I... owe... you.
莫堥蒂無罪釋放  中央法庭驚人的判決
驚天罪犯
如何
他如何脫罪
莫堥蒂消失了
萊辛巴赫英雄接下來又如何
兩個月後
您的卡出現問題
請稍等
感謝您的耐心
約翰
第歐根尼俱樂部
打擾下  我找麥考夫·福爾摩斯
Excuse me, I'm looking for Mycroft Holmes?
請問他在不在
Would you happen to know if he's around at all?
你聽不見我說話嗎
Can you not hear me?
好吧  有人知道嗎
Yes, all right. Anyone?
誰知道...
Anyone at all know...
麥考夫·福爾摩斯在哪  有人叫我在這等他
where Mycroft Holmes is, I've been asked to meet him here?
沒人理我  好吧
No takers, right.
我是透明的嗎  你們看得見我麼
Am I invisible, can you actually see me?
多謝兩位  有人叫我來找麥考夫·福爾摩斯
Thanks, gents. I've been asked to meet Mycroft Holmes.
搞什麼飛機
What the hell?!
傳統嘛  約翰  傳統界定了我們
Tradition, John, our traditions define us.
不准講話算哪門子傳統
So total silence is traditional, is it?
連句"把糖遞給我"都不能說嗎
You can't even say pass the sugar?
大半個外交部門
Three- quarters of the diplomatic service
和半個政府議會要員在一起喝茶
and half the government front bench all sharing one tea trolley,
這對大家都好  相信我
it's for the best, believe me.
我們可不想重演1972年的事
We don't want a repeat of... 1972.
血色星期天事件
- 不過在這可以說話  - 你看這個
- But we can talk in here. - You read this stuff?
挺有意思
Caught my eye.
週六他們要爆個猛料
Saturday, they're doing a big expose.
真好奇她從哪拿到的這些信息
I'd love to know where she got her information.
一個叫布魯克的人  認識麼
Someone called Brook. Recognise the name?
可能是校友吧
School friend, maybe?
夏洛克的校友
Of Sherlock's?
不過這不是我叫你來的原因
But that's not why I asked you here.
- 這誰  - 不認識嗎
- Who's that? - Don't know?
- 不認識  - 沒見過他
- No. - Never seen his face before?
他剛住到貝克街  就和你隔了兩戶人家
He's taken a flat in Baker Street, two doors down from you.
我正想拜訪下鄰居呢
I was thinking of doing a drinks thing for the neighbours.
我看還是算了
I'm not sure you'll want to.
蘇萊曼尼  阿爾巴尼亞職業殺手
Sulejmani, Albanian hit squad, expertly trained killer,
就住在離你家不到20尺的地方
living less than 20 feet from your front door.
那地段很好  坐地鐵很方便
Well, it's a great location. Jubilee line's handy.
- 約翰  - 這跟我有什麼關係
- John... - What's it got to do with me?
德琴科·盧德米拉
Dyachenko Ludmila.
- 我好像見過她  - 俄國殺手
- Actually, I think I have seen her. - Russian killer.
住你家對面
She's taken the flat opposite.
好吧
Ok.
我有點明白你的意思了
I'm sensing a pattern here.
其實  四個國際頂級刺客都搬到了
In fact, four top international assassins relocate
221B附近
to within spitting distance of 221b.
有什麼想告訴我的麼
Anything you'd care to share with me?
我該搬家了嗎
I'm moving?
不難猜到他們的共同之處
It's not hard to guess the common denominator, is it?
你覺得是莫堥蒂安排的嗎
You think this is Moriarty?
他跟夏洛克說他一定會回來
He promised Sherlock he'd come back.
如果這是莫堥蒂的傑作  我們早就死了
If this was Moriarty, we'd be dead already.
如果不是莫堥蒂  那又是誰
If not Moriarty, then who?
你既然這麼擔心他  怎麼不去找夏洛克談談
Why don't you talk to Sherlock, if you're so concerned about him?
天吶  別說了
God, don't tell me.
我們之間有太多事  約翰
Too much history between us, John.
舊賬  憤恨
Old scores, resentments.
偷走了他的藍精靈  還是弄壞了他的機動戰士
Nicked all his Smurfs? Broke his Action Man?
看完了
Finished.
我們都知道要發生什麼  約翰
We both know what's coming, John.
莫堥蒂不會罷休  他發誓要幹掉他唯一的敵手
Moriarty is obsessed, he's sworn to destroy his only rival.
所以你要我去照看你弟弟
So you want me to watch out for your brother
就因為他不會接受你的幫助
because he won't accept your help?
希望不會太麻煩你
If it's not too much trouble?
- 借過  - 抱歉
- Excuse me. - Sorry.
夏洛克  有件怪事...
Sherlock, something weird...
怎麼回事
What's going on?
- 綁架案  - 駐美大使路法斯·布盧爾
- Kidnapping. - Rufus Bruhl. The ambassador to the US.
他不是在華盛頓嗎
He's in Washington, isn't he?
不是他  是他的孩子
Not him, his children.
麥斯和克勞黛  一個七歲  一個九歲
Max and Claudette, age seven and nine.
- 他們在聖艾爾代茨  - 薩堸p的豪華寄宿學校
- They're at St Aldates. - Posh boarding place in Surrey.
學校放假  其他寄宿生都回家了
School broke up, all the boarders went home.
只有幾個孩子留校  就包括他倆
Just a few kids remained, including those two.
兩個孩子不見了
The kids have vanished.
大使親自指名找你
The ambassador's asked for you personally.
萊辛巴赫英雄
The Reichenbach hero.
跟名人一起辦案真不錯啊
Isn't it great to be working with a celebrity?
應該很快就能放你走了  謝謝
We shouldn't need to keep you for much longer. Thank you.
- 沒事了  - 麥肯齊小姐是舍監  溫柔點
- It's all right. - Miss MacKenzie, House Mistress. Go easy.
麥肯齊小姐  你負責學生的安全
Miss MacKenzie, you're in charge of pupil welfare,
可昨晚卻有人輕易闖入
yet you left this place wide open last night.
你是白癡  喝醉了  還是同夥
What are you, an idiot, a drunk or a criminal?!
立刻  迅速  回答我
Now, quickly, tell me!
門窗都關好了
All the doors and the windows were properly bolted.
昨晚沒有任何人  包括我都沒進過他們的房間
No- one, not even me, went into their room last night.
你得相信我
You have to believe me!
我相信  我就是想讓你快點說
I do, I just wanted you to speak quickly.
麥肯齊小姐需要個口袋呼吸
Miss MacKenzie will need to breath into a bag now.
每學期六千塊
Six grand a term,
居然還不能保證孩子的安全
you'd expect them to keep the kids safe for you.
你說其他的孩子都放假走了
You said the other kids had all left on their holidays.
只有他們倆還住在這層樓上
They were the only two sleeping on this floor.
完全沒有強行闖入的跡象
There's absolutely no sign of a break- in.
闖入者肯定是藏在什麼地方了
The intruder must have been hidden inside some place.
格林童話
帶我去哥哥的房間
Show me where the brother slept.
小男孩每晚都睡在這兒
The boy sleeps there every night.
盯著從走廊投進來的唯一光線
Gazing at the only light source outside in the corridor.
他會認出每個人的形態和輪廓
He'd recognise every shape, every outline,
每一個走到門前的人的剪影
the silhouette of everyone who came to the door.
那又如何
OK, so?
那樣  如果有一個他沒見過的人走到門前
So if someone approaches the door who he doesn't recognise,
就知道是闖入者  或許他都能看到武器的輪廓
an intruder, maybe he can even see the outline of a weapon.
他會怎麼做
What would he do?
在他們闖進來之前珍貴的幾秒鐘內
In the precious few seconds before they came into the room,
他如果沒有大聲呼救  會怎麼做
how would he use them if not to cry out?
這個小男孩  就是這個小男孩
This little boy, this particular little boy,
他讀了那麼多間諜小說  他會怎麼做
who reads all of those spy books, what would he do?
留下什麼標記嗎
He'd leave a sign?
叫安德森來
Get Anderson!
幫幫我們
亞麻油
Linseed oil.
沒什麼用  不能幫我們找到綁匪
Not much use, it doesn't lead us to the kidnapper.
很不錯  安德森
Brilliant, Anderson.
- 是嗎  - 是啊  很不錯地展現了白癡的風範
- Really? - Yes, brilliant impression of an idiot.
看地板
Floor.
他為我們留下了足跡
He... made a trail for us.
男孩被逼著走在他們前面
The boy was made to walk ahead of them.
怎麼  因為踮腳了嗎
On what, tiptoe?
不安的表現
Indicates anxiety.
有人拿槍指著他的腦袋
Gun held to his head.
女孩被人拉著側身走在他旁邊
The girl was pulled beside him, dragged sideways.
他的胳膊架在她的脖子上
He had his left arm cradled about her neck.
就到這了  我們不知道他們接下來去哪了
That's the end of it, we don't know where they went from here.
到底還是沒什麼用
Tells us nothing after all.
說得對  安德森  是沒什麼用
You're right, Anderson, nothing.
只讓我們知道他的鞋碼  身高  步法和步速
Except his shoe size, his height, his gait, his walking pace.
玩得開心嗎
Having fun?
現在開心了
Starting to.
或許還是別笑的好  畢竟有小孩被綁了
Maybe don't do the smiling. Kidnapped children?
如果門都鎖上了  他怎麼躲過的監視器
How could he get past the CCTV? If all the doors were locked.
他門沒鎖的時候就進來了
He walked in when they weren't locked.
但那種學校哪會讓陌生人隨意進出
But a stranger can't just walk into a school like that.
只要時機對  任何人都能隨意進出任何地方
Anyone can walk in anywhere if they pick the right moment.
昨天是期末
Yesterday, end of term,
到處是家長  司機  員工
parents milling around, chauffeurs, staff.
他們中間再混進個陌生人誰會察覺
What's one more stranger among that lot?
他伺機行事
He was waiting for them.
只要找個好地方藏身即可
All he had to do was find a place to hide.
聖巴塞洛繆醫院
茉莉
Molly!
你好啊  我正要出去
Hello, I'm just going out.
- 不  你不出去  - 我午飯約了人
- No, you're not. - I've got a lunch date.
- 取消吧  我們一起吃午餐  - 啥
- Cancel it, you're having lunch with me. - What?
我需要你的幫助
I need your help.
事關你的一個前男友  我們正在追查他的下落
It's one of your old boyfriends, we're trying to track him down.
他近來有些搗蛋
He's been a bit naughty.
- 是莫堥蒂干的嗎  - 當然是他
- It's Moriarty? - Of course it's Moriarty!
其實金算不上是我男朋友
Jim actually wasn't even my boyfriend,
我們只約會過三次  我沒再和他交往了
we went out three times. I ended it.
是啊  然後他去偷走了王冠和權杖
Yes, then he stole the Crown Jewels,
闖進英國央行
broke into the Bank of England
還組織了本頓維爾監獄的越獄
and organised a prison break in Pentonville.
為了維護法紀和秩序  我建議你
For the sake of law and order, I suggest you
將來就不要找男朋友了  茉莉
avoid all future attempts at a relationship, Molly.
那些油漬  約翰  綁匪腳印堛漯o漬
Oil, John. The oil in the kidnapper's footprint.
會幫我們找到莫堥蒂
It'll lead us to Moriarty.
他鞋上所有的化學品都保存了下來
All the chemical traces on his shoe have been preserved.
鞋底就好像護照
The sole of the shoe is like a passport.
如果我們走運  能查到他最近的全部行蹤
If we're lucky, we'll see everything he's been up to.
那個需要做分析
I need that analysis.
是堿性的
Alkaline.
- 謝謝你  約翰  - 是茉莉
- Thank you, John. - Molly.
是啊
Yes.
白堊
瀝青
磚塵
植物
我欠你的
I... o... u.
甘油分子
Glycerol molecule.
甘油
甘油  丙烷  1,2,3  三醇  3羥基官能團
是什麼東西
What are you?
你說"我欠你的"是什麼意思
What did you mean, IOU?
你剛剛說"我欠你的"
You said IOU.
你剛剛一直在念叨這幾個字
You were muttering it while you were working.
沒什麼  記下來的東西罷了
Nothing, mental note.
你有點像我爸  他死了  哦不  抱歉
You're a bit like my dad. He's dead. No, sorry.
茉莉  請不要覺得非得跟我搭訕
Molly, please don't feel the need to make conversation,
這真不是你的強項
it's really not your area.
他死前那段日子  總是很開心  心情愉悅
When he was dying, he was always cheerful, he was lovely,
可他以為沒人看到他時就不是這樣了
except when he thought no- one could see.
- 我有次看到他的樣子  很哀傷  - 茉莉
- I saw him once, he looked sad. - Molly.
你就很哀傷  當你以為他看不到你的時候
You look sad, when you think he can't see you.
你沒事吧  別說你沒事
Are you OK? And don't just say you are,
因為我知道那種表情的含義
because I know what that means,
以為沒人看著你時就流露哀傷的含義
looking sad when you think no- one can see you.
- 你就能看見我  - 我對你不算數
- You can see me. - I don't count.
我只是想說  如果我能做什麼
What I'm trying to say is, that if there's anything I can do,
你需要我做任何事  我都會幫你
anything you need, anything at all, you can have me.
不是  我就是說  我是說
No, I just mean, I mean,
如果你需要我做什麼事  我都可以
if there's anything you need, it's fine.
但我會需要你做什麼
But what can I need from you?
沒什麼  我不知道
Nothing. I don't know.
其實你大可只說句謝謝
You could probably say thank you, actually.
那謝謝了
Thank you?
我要去買點薯片吃
I'm just going to go and get some crisps.
你想吃什麼嗎
Do you want anything?
算了  我知道你不吃
It's OK, I know you don't.
- 其實  要不我...  - 我知道你不吃
- Well, actually, maybe I'll... - I know you don't.
夏洛克
Sherlock?
箱子堛漕滬茷H封
This envelope that was in her trunk,
- 還有一個  - 什麼
- there's another one. - What?
今天有人放在我們門階上  沒錯  你瞧啊
On our doorstep. Found it today. Yes, and look at that.
你瞧  是完全相同的封印
Look at that, exactly the same seal.
- 麵包屑  - 我回來的時候就放在那兒
- Breadcrumbs. - It was there when I got back.
麵包屑留下的行跡
A little trace of breadcrumbs.
那本精裝童話書
Hardback copy of Fairy Tales.
格林童話
兩個孩子被邪惡的父親領進了林子
Two children led into the forest by a wicked father,
他們跟著麵包屑走
follow a little trail of breadcrumbs.
糖果屋
是《糖果屋》的故事
That's Hansel and Gretel.
什麼樣的綁匪還留下線索
What sort of kidnapper leaves clues?
喜歡自吹自擂的綁匪
The sort that likes to boast,
他把這一切看作是個遊戲
the sort that thinks it's all a game.
他坐在我們的公寓  對我說的原話是
He sat in our flat and he said these exact words to me...
每個童話故事都要有個老派的壞蛋
"All fairy tales need a good old- fashioned villain."
第五樣物質  是童話的一部分
The fifth substance, it's part of the tale.
- 女巫的房子  - 啥
- The witch's house. - What?
甘油分子
The glycerol molecule.
聚甘油蓖麻醇酯
是聚甘油蓖麻醇酯
PGPR!
- 那是什麼  - 是用來做巧克力的
- What's that? - It's used in making chocolate.
這是一小時前傳真過來的
This fax arrived an hour ago.
快點啊
他們要死了
你查到了什麼
What have you got for us?
我們要找出城堛漱@個地方
We need to find a place in the city
這五樣東西在那埵野瘨
where all five of these things intersect.
白堊  瀝青  磚塵  植物
Chalk, asphalt, brick dust, vegetation.
這是什麼  巧克力
What is this? Chocolate?!
我認為我們要找的是一間廢棄的糖果廠
I think we're looking for a disused sweet factory.
我們得縮小範圍  有瀝青的糖果廠呢
We need to narrow that down. A sweet factory with asphalt?
不行  還是太泛泛  得有更具體的東西
No, no, no, no, too general. Something more specific.
白堊  白堊質粘土  這樣能縮小地理範圍
Chalk, chalky clay. That's a far thinner band of geology.
磚塵
Brick dust?
建築工地  五十年代的磚頭
Building site. Bricks from the 1950s.
倫敦有幾千個建築工地
There's thousands of building sites in London.
- 我派人出去找了  - 我也有
- I've got people out looking. - So have I!
流浪漢的信息網  比警方敏捷多了
Homeless network, faster than the police,
也不介意收受賄賂
far more relaxed about taking bribes.
約翰
John.
彭土杜鵑  符合要求
Rhododendron ponticum. Matches.
白堊
磚塵
植物
巧克力
阿德斯頓
- 阿德斯頓  - 啥
- Addlestone. - What?
距離河和公園一英里的地方
There's a mile of disused factories
有處廢棄廠房  符合所有要求
between the river and the park, it matches everything.
好吧  行動  行動
Right, come on. Come on!
好了  你們去那邊看
OK, you look over there.
不要有疏漏
Look everywhere.
大家請散開  散開
OK, spread out, please, spread out.
剛剛熄滅的  他們還在這兒
This was alight moments ago. They're still here!
糖紙
Sweet wrappers?
他給你們吃什麼了  漢塞爾和格萊特
What's he been feeding you? Hansel and Gretel.
- 水銀  - 什麼
- Mercury. - What?
糖紙  上面塗了水銀  是有毒的
The papers, they're painted with mercury, lethal.
他們吃得越多
The more they ate...
就會要了他們的命
It was killing them.
但是單個不足以致命
But it's not enough to kill them on its own.
如果攝入足夠多的量  最終會導致他們死亡
Taken in large enough quantities, eventually it would kill them.
他不需要親自來行刑
He didn't need to be there for the execution.
遙控殺人  他可以待在千里之外
Murder by remote control, he could be 1,000 miles away.
他們越餓  吃得越多
The hungrier they got, the more they ate,
就死得越快  真漂亮
the faster they died. Neat.
- 控制一下  - 在這邊
- Sherlock. - Over here!
我會照顧他  別擔心
I've got him, don't worry.
好了  專業人士都問完了
Right then, the professionals are finished.
要是外行還想進去自己問問
If the amateurs want to go in and have their turn.
記住  她受了驚嚇  而且只有七歲
Now remember, she's in shock and she's just seven years old,
所以  如果你能...
so, anything you can do to...
- 別太夏洛克嗎  - 對  可能會比較好
- Not be myself? - Yeah, might be helpful.
克勞黛  我
Claudette, I...
別這樣  我知道你很害怕
No, no, I know it's been hard for you.
- 克勞黛  聽著  - 出去  出去
- Claudette, listen to me. - Out. Get out!
- 這沒道理啊  - 孩子受驚過度
- Makes no sense. - Kid's traumatised.
夏洛克某些地方讓她想起那個綁匪
Something about Sherlock reminds her of the kidnapper.
她說什麼了嗎
What's she said?
一個字都沒說
Hasn't uttered another syllable.
- 那個男孩呢  - 還是昏迷不醒
- And the boy? - No, he's unconscious.
仍在重癥監護中
He's still in intensive care.
別往心堨h
Well, don't let it get to you,
每次看你進門  我都想尖叫
I always feel like screaming when you walk into a room.
說實話很多人都有同感
In fact, so do most people.
走吧
Come on.
只憑腳印你就找到了那些孩子  了不起
Brilliant work you did finding those kids from just a footprint,
真是太神奇了
it's really amazing.
謝謝
Thank you.
難以置信
Unbelievable.
- 你還好嗎  - 在思考
- You OK? - Thinking.
我坐這輛  你等下輛吧
This is my cab, you get the next one.
- 為什麼  - 你會說話
- Why? - You might talk.
"這是巧克力嗎"
'Is this chocolate?'
"我們要找的是一家廢棄的糖果廠"
'We're looking for a disused sweet factory.'
"出去"
'Get out!'
有問題嗎
Problem?
倫敦出租車購物廣告
This stunning evening wear
為您呈現這套華美的晚裝配件
set from us here at London Taxi Shopping.
請把它關掉好嗎
Can you turn this off, please?
如您所見  這套配件包括一副美麗的...
As you can see, the set comprises of a beautiful...
把這關掉行不行
Can you turn this off?!
搭配四條鑲嵌式鑽石手鏈
Accompanied by four spangly diamond bracelets...
你好
Hello.
準備好聽故事了嗎
Are you ready for the story?
這是自誇騎士的故事
This is the story of Sir Boast- a- lot.
一個腳印  這就是他所有的線索
A footprint, it's all he had.
一個腳印
A footprint.
是啊  你也知道他的能耐
Yeah, well, you know what he's like.
貝克街犯罪現場調查專家
CSI Baker Street.
可我們的人就做不到
Well, our boys couldn't have done it.
所以我們需要他  他更厲害
Well, that's why we need him, he's better.
這只是一種解釋
That's one explanation.
還有別的解釋嗎
And what's the other?
自誇騎士是圓桌騎士中
Sir Boast- a- lot was the bravest
最勇敢  也是最聰明的騎士
and cleverest knight at the round table.
但其他騎士逐漸開始厭倦他那些
But soon the other knights began to grow tired of his stories
講述他多麼英勇
about how brave he was
頌揚他屠龍偉業的故事
and how many dragons he'd slain.
很快他們就開始懷疑
And soon they began to wonder,
自誇爵士的故事究竟是不是真的
"Are Sir Boast- a- lot's stories even true?"
只有他能找到那些證據
Only he could have found that evidence.
不  不
No. No
那女孩看到他時  叫得撕心裂肺
The girl screams her head off when she sees him...
她可從來沒見過他
A man she has never seen before,
除非她以前見過他
unless she had seen him before.
你究竟想說什麼
What's your point?
你知道我想說什麼  你只是不想相信
You know what it is, you just don't want to think about it.
於是所有的騎士都去對亞瑟王說
So, all of the knights went to King Arthur and said,
"我不相信自誇騎士的故事"
'I don't believe Sir Boast- a- lot's stories.'
"他就是個大騙子"
'He's just a big old liar'
"都是他編的故事  讓自己顯得很了不起"
'who makes things up to make himself look good.
你們不會真以為是他幹的吧
You're not seriously suggesting he's involved, are you?
我認為我們得考慮這種可能性
I think we have to entertain the possibility.
後來  甚至連國王也開始懷疑
And then, even the King began to wonder.
但自誇騎士的最終問題還不是這個
But that wasn't the end of Sir Boast- a- lot's problem.
不
No.
這還不是他的最終問題
That wasn't the final problem.
故事講完了
The end.
停車
Stop the cab.
Stop the cab!
那是怎麼回事
What was that?!
那是什麼
What was that?
不要錢了
No charge.
小心
Watch out!
謝謝
Thank you.
夏洛克
Sherlock!
是他  是那個人
That is him. It's him.
叫蘇萊曼尼什麼的
Sulejmani or something,
麥考夫給我看過他的檔案
Mycroft showed me his file.
他是阿爾巴尼亞的黑幫大佬
He's a big Albanian gangster,
住的地方跟我們只隔兩戶
lives two doors down from us.
- 他因為跟我握手而被殺  - 什麼意思
- He died because I shook his hand. - What do you mean?
他救了我的命  卻不能碰我  為什麼
He saved my life, but he couldn't touch me. Why?
我們家門口就住著四個殺手
Four assassins living right on our doorstep.
他們不是來殺我的
They haven't come here to kill me.
他們必須保住我的命
They have to keep me alive.
我手上有他們都想要的東西
I've got something that all of them want.
但如果他們中任何一個接近我
But if one of them approaches me,
其他人就會殺死他
The others kill them before they can get it.
選擇您要使用的網絡
從以下列表中選擇您要使用的網絡 必要時請輸入網絡密碼
所有注意力都在我身上
All of the attention is focused on me.
一張嚴密的監控網正監視著我們
There's a surveillance web closing in on us right now.
你手上究竟有什麼東西這麼重要
So what have you got that's so important?
我得問問除塵的狀況
I need to ask about the dusting.
要精確的細節  上個星期哪堻Q清掃過
Precise details, in the last week, what's been cleaned?
星期二  我清理了你的地毯
Tuesday, I did your lino.
不  是這  我們要在這個房間找
No, in here, this room, this is where we'll find it.
任何灰塵被擦拭的痕跡
Any break in the dust line.
什麼都能歸位  但灰塵不行
You can put back anything but dust.
灰塵即鐵證
Dust is eloquent.
他這是要做什麼
What is it all about?
找攝像頭  我們被監視了
Cameras, we're being watched.
什麼  攝像頭  在這兒嗎
What?! Cameras? Here?
我穿著睡衣呢
I'm in my nightie!
- 不  探長  - 怎麼了
- No, Inspector. - Why?
- 我的回答是不  - 我什麼都沒問呢
- The answer's no. - You've not heard the question!
你想把我帶到警署去
You want to take me to the station.
就不麻煩你開口問了
Just saving you the trouble of asking.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
- 因為那聲尖叫  - 是的
- The scream? - Yeah.
是誰說的  多諾萬  肯定是多諾萬
Who was it? Donovan? I bet it was Donovan.
我是否與綁架案有牽連
"Am I somehow responsible for the kidnapping?"
莫堥蒂很聰明
Moriarty is smart.
他在她腦海奡茪J懷疑的種子
He planted that doubt in her head.
那種感覺縈繞不去
That little nagging sensation.
很難抗拒
You're going to have to be strong to resist.
你沒法扼殺一種想法  對吧
You can't kill an idea, can you?
只要它在這  生根發芽
Not once it's made a home... there.
你會跟我走嗎
Will you come?
他的下一步棋  是一張照片
One photograph, that's his next move.
莫堥蒂的遊戲
Moriarty's game.
先是孩子的尖叫
First the scream,
然後是我被帶去問訊的照片
then a photograph of me being taken in for questioning.
他想一點一點地毀了我
He wants to destroy me inch by inch.
這是一場遊戲  雷斯垂德
It is a game, Lestrade,
而我並不想參與
and not one I'm willing to play.
代我向多諾萬警佐問好
Give my regards to Sergeant Donovan.
- 他們會作出決定  - 什麼決定
- They'll be deciding. - Deciding?
是否帶著逮捕令回來逮捕我
Whether to come back with a warrant and arrest me.
你這麼覺得嗎
You think?
這是標準程序
Standard procedure.
你應該跟他走  別人會以為...
You should have gone with him. People'll think...
我才不在乎別人怎麼想
I don't care what people think.
但你不想讓他們認為你很蠢  或犯了錯
You'd care if they thought you were stupid or wrong.
不  是他們蠢  他們犯了錯
No, that would just make them stupid or wrong.
夏洛克  我不想讓這個世界以為你是...
Sherlock, I don't want the world believing you're...
以為我是什麼
That I am what?
騙子
A fraud.
- 你擔心他們是對的  - 什麼
- You're worried they're right. - What?
- 你擔心他們對我的判斷是對的  - 不
- That they're right about me. - No.
這就是你煩躁的原因
That's why you're upset.
你不能不考慮  他們或許是對的
You can't entertain the possibility they may be right.
- 你害怕自己也受了騙  - 我沒有
- You're afraid you've been taken in as well. - No, no.
莫堥蒂也在玩弄你的思想
Moriarty is playing with your mind, too.
你難道看不出是怎麼回事嗎
Can't you SEE what's going on?!
不  我認識的是真實的你
No, I know you for real.
百分之百嗎
100 percent?
誰會一直假裝成這麼個討厭鬼
Well, nobody could fake being such an annoying dick all the time.
- 夏洛克·福爾摩斯  - 是的  長官
- Sherlock Holmes? - Yes, sir.
媒體上經常報道的那個傢伙
That bloke that's been in the press?
我以為他是個私家偵探
I thought he was some sort of private eye.
- 他是的  - 我們一直都在向他咨詢
- He is. - We've been consulting with him,
你是這個意思嗎
that's what you're telling me?
我們沒有讓他插手過機要案件吧
Not used him on any proper cases though, have we?
有那麼一兩個吧
Well, one or two.
或許是二三十個
Or 20 or 30.
什麼
What?!
不是只有我這麼做  格雷格森...
I'm not the only senior officer who did this. Gregson...
閉嘴
Shut up!
一個業餘偵探
An amateur detective
居然能接觸到各種機密信息
given access to all sorts of classified information.
現在他還是一個案件的疑犯
And now he's a suspect in a case.
- 恕我直言  - 你這個白癡  雷斯垂德
- With all due respect... - You're a bloody idiot, Lestrade!
現在就去把他抓來  就現在
Now go and fetch him in, right now.
去抓他
Do it!
現在你們得意了
Proud of yourselves?
要是不止這一個案子呢
Well, what if it's not just this case?
要是每次他都是在耍我們呢
What if he's done this to us every single time?
警局媮椄O有人護著我們的  是雷斯垂德
So, still got some friends on the force. It's Lestrade.
他說他們正趕過來
Says they're all coming over here now.
所有被你弄得沒面子的警官
Queuing up to slap on the handcuffs.
都排著隊要來拷你呢
Every officer you've ever made feel like a tit,
那可是不少人呢
which is a lot of people.
抱歉  是不是打擾你們了
Sorry, am I interrupting?
有人送來一個包裹  我給忘了
Some chap delivered a parcel, I forgot,
上面標記說易腐爛
marked perishable.
我只好簽收了
I had to sign for it.
名字挺滑稽  是德語  像是童話堛
Funny name, German, like the fairy tales.
燒焦了
Burnt to a crisp.
這是什麼意思
What does it mean?
- 警察  - 我去開門
- Police! - I'll go.
夏洛克
Sherlock.
- 抱歉  赫德森太太  - 我們得談談
- Excuse me, Mrs Hudson. - We need to talk to you.
別就這麼闖進來呀
Don't barge in like that!
你們有逮捕令嗎  有嗎
Have you got a warrant? Have you?
別插手  約翰
Leave it, John.
講點禮貌
Manners!
夏洛克·福爾摩斯  我現在
Sherlock Holmes, I'm arresting you
以涉嫌誘拐和綁架的罪名逮捕你
on suspicion of abduction and kidnapping.
- 沒關係  約翰  - 他沒有反抗
- It's OK, John. He's not resisting...
不  這怎麼會沒關係  這太荒謬了
No, it's not all right, this is ridiculous.
現在帶他下樓
Get him downstairs now.
你真不該這麼做
You really don't have to do this.
別妨礙公務  不然我連你一起逮捕
Don't try to interfere or I shall arrest you too.
你滿意了嗎
You done?
我早就說過
I said it.
- 我們初次見面的時候  - 算了吧
- First time we met. - Don't bother.
他不會滿足於破案
Solving crimes won't be enough.
總有一天  他會越過底線
One day he'll cross the line.
你自己想想  什麼人會去綁架孩子
Now ask yourself, what sort of man would kidnap those kids
就為了通過找回他們來顯擺自己
just so he can impress us all by finding them?
- 多諾萬  - 長官
- Donovan? - Sir?
- 人抓住了嗎  - 是的  長官
- Got our man? - Yes, sir.
要我說的話  看著他就覺得古怪
Looked a bit of a weirdo, if you ask me.
這種義警通常都這樣
Often are, these vigilante types.
你看什麼呢
What are you looking at?
你還好嗎  長官
Are you all right, sir?
- 來跟我作伴了  - 是的
- Joining me? - Yeah.
顯然打總警司一拳
Well, apparently it's against the law
屬於違法行為
to chin the Chief Superintendent.
這可不太聰明
Bit awkward this.
這下沒人來保釋我們了
There's no- one to bail us.
我更傾向於現在就大膽逃跑
I was thinking more about our imminent and daring escape.
- 所有單位到27區  - 什麼
- All units to 27. - What?
所有單位到2
All units to 2...
女士們  先生們  請你們趴下好嗎
Ladies and gentlemen, will you all please get on your knees?
- 最好現在就趴下  - 照他說的做
- NOW would be good! - Do as he says!
提醒你們一聲  槍是他奪的
Just so you're aware, the gun is his idea,
我就是個  你知道
I'm just a... you know.
我的人質
My hostage.
人質  沒錯  這個可以有
Hostage, yes, that works.
這個可以有
That works.
現在怎麼辦
So what now?
如莫堥蒂所願  做個逃犯  跑
Doing what Moriarty wants, becoming a fugitive. Run!
追上他  雷斯垂德
Get after him, Lestrade!
抓緊我的手
Take my hand.
這下肯定要被人閒話了
Now people will definitely talk.
- 槍掉了  - 別管了
- The gun! - Leave it!
夏洛克  等等
Sherlock, wait!
我們得協調一致才行
We're going to need to coordinate.
往右邊去  往你右邊去
Go to your right. Go to your right.
每個人都寧可信其有
Everybody wants to believe it,
這就是其高明之處
that's what makes it so clever.
一個比真相更受人青睞的謊言
A lie that's preferable to the truth.
我的演繹法是騙人的
My deductions were a sham.
大家都舒坦了  夏洛克毫無過人之處
No- one feels inadequate, Sherlock's an ordinary man.
麥考夫  他能幫我們
Mycroft, he could help us.
現在真不是打親情牌的好時機
Big family reconciliation, now's not really the moment.
夏洛克
Sherlock...
有人跟來了
we're being followed.
我就知道躲不過警察
I knew we couldn't outrun the police.
那人不是警察
That's not the police,
是咱們貝克街上的新鄰居
it's one of my new neighbours from Baker Street.
看他能不能給我們答案
Let's see if he can give us some answers.
我們去哪兒
Where are we going?
我們要衝到那輛巴士前面
We're going to jump in front of that bus.
你想從我這堭o到什麼
Tell me what you want from me.
告訴我
Tell me!
他放在你公寓堣F
He left it at your flat.
- 誰  - 莫堥蒂
- Who? - Moriarty.
放了什麼
What?
- 程序代碼  - 這就對了
- The computer key code. - Of course.
他公開售賣
He's selling it.
闖進倫敦塔的程序
The programme he used to break into the Tower.
他是在來的時候動的手腳
He planted it when he came around.
它可以扭轉局面
It's a game- changer.
它是把鑰匙  能攻破任何系統
It's a key, it can break into any system
此時此刻就在我們公寓
and it's sitting in our flat right now.
所以他留下那個信息
That's why he left that message,
告訴大家該去哪  "去找夏洛克"
telling everyone where to come, "Get Sherlock!"
我們必須回公寓找到它
We need to get back into the flat and search.
刑事調查局在那守著
CID will be camped out.
為什麼栽贓給你
Why plant it on you?
又一個搞壞我名聲的歪點子
It's another subtle way of smearing my name,
現在我成了那些罪行的最大嫌疑人
now I'm best pals with all those criminals.
你看過這個嗎
Yeah, well, have you seen this?
大爆料
A kiss- and- tell.
夏洛克  駭人聽聞的真相
密友理查·布魯克徹底坦白
一個叫理查·布魯克的傢伙
Some bloke called Rich Brook.
這人是誰
Who is he?
現在發表聲明是不是太晚了
Too late to go on the record?
恭喜了  "夏洛克·福爾摩斯的真相"
Congratulations, "The Truth About Sherlock Holmes."
誰都想要的獨家  而你搞到了  漂亮
The scoop that everybody wanted and you got it. Bravo!
我給過你機會
I gave you your opportunity.
我本想站在你這邊  記得嗎
I wanted to be on your side, remember?
你拒絕了我  所以...
You turned me down, so...
然後就有大驚喜  有人爆出猛料
Then lo and behold, someone spills all the beans.
真是心想事成  布魯克是誰
How utterly convenient. Who is Brook?
說吧  姬蒂  鬼才相信電話爆料
Come on, Kitty, no- one trusts the voice at the end of a phone.
毫無疑問  咖啡館婺I面
All those little meetings in cafes,
酒店房間媟|談
those sessions in the hotel room
他對著採訪機侃侃而談
when he gabbled into your Dictaphone.
你怎麼就相信他了呢
How do you know that you can trust him?
一個揣著聖盃冒出來的傢伙
A man turns up with the Holy Grail in his pockets.
他怎麼讓你信服的呢
What were his credentials?
親愛的  買不到咖啡粉煮的
Darling, they didn't have any ground coffee,
我就買了普通的
so I just got normal.
你說過他們不可能找到這堥
You said that they wouldn't find me here,
你說過我在這堳雃w全
you said that I'd be safe here.
你很安全
You are safe.
理查  我是證人
Richard, I'm a witness,
他們不會當著證人的面傷害你
they wouldn't harm you in front of witnesses.
這就是你的爆料人
So that's your source?
莫堥蒂就是理查·布魯克
Moriarty is Richard Brook?
他就是理查·布魯克  不存在莫堥蒂
Of course he's Richard Brook, there is no Moriarty.
從來就沒有這個人
There never has been.
- 你說什麼胡話  - 仔細看看他
- What are you talking about? - Look him up.
理查·布魯克  夏洛克雇來扮演莫堥蒂的人
Rich Brook, an actor Sherlock Holmes hired to be Moriarty.
華生醫生  我知道你是好人
Dr Watson, I know you're a good man,
不要  不要傷害我
don't, don't, don't hurt me.
不對  你是莫堥蒂  他就是莫堥蒂
No, you are Moriarty! He's Moriarty!
我們見過  記得嗎  你想把我炸死
We've met, remember? You were going to blow me up!
對不起  對不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
他出錢雇我  而我需要活兒
He paid me, I needed the work.
我是個演員  我失業了
I'm an actor, I was out of work.
夏洛克  你最好解釋一下
Sherlock, you'd better explain,
我完全搞不懂了
because I am not getting this.
我來解釋吧  白紙黑字
I'll be doing the explaining, in print.
全在這  板上釘釘的證據
It's all here, conclusive proof.
夏洛克是個騙子
他策劃了所有的罪案
你虛構出金姆斯·莫堥蒂  所謂的夙敵
You invented James Moriarty, your nemesis.
虛構出來的
Invented him?!
事實上所有的罪案都是他策劃的
He invented all the crimes, actually.
最厲害的是憑空造出一位犯罪大師
And to cap it all, he made up a master villain.
- 這太扯了  - 問他啊
- Don't be ridiculous! - Ask him.
他就在這  問他啊
He's right here. Just ask him.
- 告訴他  理查  - 得了吧  他上過庭
- Tell him, Richard. - For God's sake, this man was on trial!
沒錯  就是你付錢讓他背黑鍋
Yes, and you paid him, pay him to take the rap.
還保證搞定陪審團
Promised you'd rig the jury.
雖然不是倫敦西區的角色  但我猜錢也不少
Not exactly a West End role, but I'll bet the money was good.
但也不夠多  否則他不會爆料
But not so good he didn't want to sell his story.
對不起  誠心的  非常抱歉
I am sorry. I am. I am sorry.
你準備發表的就是這個故事
So this is the story you're going to publish?
最後的結論就是
The big conclusion of it all,
莫堥蒂只是個演員
Moriarty's an actor?
他心堜白
He knows I am.
我有證據  有證據  給他們看...
I have proof. I have proof. Show them...
姬蒂  給他們看看
Kitty, show them something.
好啊  拿出來我看看
Yeah, show me something.
我上過電視  是兒童頻道
I'm on TV. I'm on kids' TV.
我講故事
I'm the story- teller.
理查·布魯克
獲獎演員參演熱門醫療劇
我講故事  出過DVD
I'm the story- teller. It's on DVD.
理查·布魯克
簡歷
告訴他
Just tell him.
反正都這樣了  不用瞞了
It's all coming out. It's all over.
告訴他們  說啊  說啊  還瞞什麼啊
Just tell them. Just tell them. Tell them! It's all over now!
不要  別碰我  你休想碰我
No! Don't you touch me! Don't you lay a finger on me!
你耍夠了吧
Stop it now!
別傷害我  不要讓他過來
Don't hurt me! Don't let him get away!
放過他
Leave him alone!
不行不行  他還有後援
No, no, no. He'll have back- up.
你知道嗎  夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Do you know what, Sherlock Holmes?
我現在算是看透你了  你讓我噁心
I look at you know and I can read you... and you repel me.
他真能做到嗎
Can he do that?
徹底改變身份  把你抹黑成罪犯
Completely change his identity, make you the criminal?
他徹底掌握了我的情況
He's got my whole life story.
要想兜售一個天大的謊言
That's what you do when you sell a big lie,
將其包裹在真相之中  看上去無懈可擊
you wrap it up in the truth to make it more palatable.
這只是你的一家之言了
It'll be your word against his.
他用一天時間在人們腦袋堮I下懷疑的種子
He's been sowing doubt into people's minds for 24 hours.
再做一件事
There's only one thing
就能結束這場遊戲  那就是...
he needs to do to complete his game and that...
夏洛克
Sherlock?
我要去做一件事
There's something I need to do.
- 什麼事  我能幫忙嗎  - 不  我得一個人干
- What? Can I help? - No, on my own.
你之前說錯了  知道嗎
You're wrong, you know?
你的確算數
You do count.
你一直都算數  我始終相信你
You've always counted and I've always trusted you.
但你也說對了
But you were right.
我的確有事
I'm not OK.
你怎麼了
Tell me what's wrong.
茉莉  我可能快死了
Molly, I think I'm going to die.
你需要什麼
What do you need?
如果我不是你所以為的樣子
If I wasn't everything that you think I am,
甚至不是我所以為的樣子
everything that I think I am...
你還願意幫我嗎
would you still want to help me?
你需要什麼
What do you need?
你
You.
她真的做了不少功課  那個萊利小姐
She has really done her homework, Miss Riley,
這些事只有和夏洛克最親近的人才知道
and it's things that only someone close to Sherlock could know.
你最近有沒有看過你弟弟的通訊錄
Have you seen your brother's address book lately?
只有兩個名字  你跟我
Two names... yours and mine...
而莫堥蒂不是從我這堭o到的
and Moriarty didn't get this stuff from me.
- 約翰  - 怎麼回事  你們什麼關係
- John... - So how does it work, your relationship?
你們是不是偶爾出去喝喝咖啡  你跟金
Do you go out for a coffee now and then, you and Jim?
你的親弟弟
Your own brother
你把他的生平故事都告訴了這個瘋子
and you blabbed about his entire life to this maniac.
我根本沒打算...我根本沒想過...
I never intend... I never dreamt...
你當時就是想跟我說這件事吧
This... this is what you were trying to tell me, isn't it?
"照看好他  因為我犯了個錯"
"Watch his back because I've made a mistake."
你怎麼認識他的
How did you meet him?
他這樣的人  我們很瞭解  盡在掌控之中
People like him, we know about them, we watch them.
但是金姆斯·莫堥蒂
But James Moriarty...
擁有前所未有的犯罪頭腦
the most dangerous criminal mind the world has ever seen,
以及最終極的武器
and, in his pocket, the ultimate weapon.
程序代碼
The key code.
區區幾行程序就能暢通無阻
A few lines of computer code that can unlock any door.
你綁架他就是為了套出代碼
And you abducted him to try and find the key code?
我們對他審問了數周
Interrogated him for weeks.
- 結果呢  - 他不合作
- And? - He wouldn't play along.
他只是坐著
He just sat there
凝視著黑暗
staring into the darkness.
唯一能讓他開口的是...
The only thing that made him open up...
我可以讓他說話  就一點點
I could get him to talk, just a little.
可是...
But...
作為回報  你把夏洛克的故事透露給他
In return you had to offer him Sherlock's life story.
所以  這個天大的謊言
So, one big lie...
夏洛克是個騙子
Sherlock's a fraud,
人們會相信  因為別的部分都是真的
and people will swallow it because the rest of it's true.
莫堥蒂想要毀了夏洛克
Moriarty wanted Sherlock destroyed, right,
而你給他送去了最強力的武器
and you have given him the perfect ammunition.
約翰
John.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
算了吧
Please!
轉告他  好嗎
Tell him, would you?
我收到你的短信
I got your message.
程序代碼是問題的關鍵
The computer code is the key to this.
把它找出來並加以使用
We find it, we can use it.
用莫堥蒂的方式擊敗他
Beat Moriarty in his own game.
你說使用是什麼意思
What do you mean use it?
他用來編造了一個假身份
He used it to create a false identity
我們也能篡改記錄  銷毀理查·布魯克
so we can break into the records and destroy Richard Brook.
把金·莫堥蒂逼回來
Bring back Jim Moriarty again.
他無罪釋放那天
Somewhere in 221b,
他把代碼藏在了221B的某個地方
somewhere on the day of the verdict he left it hidden.
- 他碰過什麼  - 一個蘋果  僅此而已
- What did he touch? - An apple, nothing else.
- 他寫了什麼嗎  - 沒有
- Did he write anything down? - No.
\h過來玩吧
\h\h\h巴茨醫院樓頂
夏·福
順便
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h帶了你也許想拿回去的東西
是我  請講
Yeah, speaking.
什麼
What?
怎麼了  她沒事吧
What happened? Is she OK?
不是吧  好  我這就來
My God! Right, yes, I'm coming.
- 什麼事  - 是醫護人員
- What is it? - Paramedics.
赫德森太太受到了槍擊
Mrs Hudson's been shot.
怎麼回事
What? How?
沒準是你引來的那些殺手  天啊
Probably one of the killers you managed to attract. Jesus! Jesus!
她不行了  夏洛克  走吧
She's dying, Sherlock. Let's go.
你去  我很忙
You go. I'm busy.
- 忙  - 思考  我需要思考
- Busy?! - Thinking. I need to think.
你需要...你一點兒都不關心她嗎
You need to...? Doesn't she mean anything to you?
上回有人碰了碰她  你就差點把他殺了
You once half- killed a man because he laid a finger on her.
- 她是我房東  - 她快死了
- She's my landlady. - She's dying...
你太冷血了
you machine!
活見鬼  你就留在這塈a  隨你便
Sod this. Sod this! You stay here if you want, on your own.
我只有孤獨作伴  孤獨能保護我
Alone is what I have. Alone protects me.
不對  保護我們的是朋友
No, friends protect people.
\h\h\h我在等著你哦
金·莫
好了
Well...
終於見面了
here we are at last.
就我們倆  夏洛克
You and me, Sherlock.
我們的問題  終極問題
And our problem... the final problem.
活著
Staying alive!
無聊透頂吧
It's so boring, isn't it?
一成不變
It's just staying.
我這輩子都在找樂子
All my life I've been searching for distractions
你曾經那麼有趣  現在也沒意思了
and you were the best distraction and now I don't even have you
因為我打敗了你
because I've beaten you.
你知道嗎
And you know what?
說到底  太簡單了
In the end, it was easy.
沒勁
It was easy.
我只能回去找普通人玩了
Now I've got to go back to playing with the ordinary people,
而到頭來  你也不過和他們一樣是個普通人
and it turns out you're ordinary, just like all of them.
好吧
Well.
你是不是開始懷疑我是不是真的了
Did you almost start to wonder if I was real?
你是不是也被我耍了啊
Did I nearly get you?
理查·布魯克
Richard Brook.
沒人看出其中的亮點  但你看出來了
Nobody seems to get the joke, but you do.
- 當然了  - 真不錯
- Of course. - Attaboy.
理查·布魯克的德語就是萊辛巴赫
Richard Brook in German is Reichenbach.
- 那個讓我出名的案子  - 只是覺得這樣很好玩啦
- The case that made my name. - Just trying to have some fun.
不錯啊  你這也看出來了
Good. You got that too.
數字一樣的節奏
Beats like digits.
每一拍就是1  其餘的都是0
Every beat is a one, every rest is a zero.
二進制代碼
Binary code.
所以那些殺手都要救我
That's why all those assassins tried to save my life.
代碼就藏在我身上  藏在我腦海
It was hidden on me, hidden inside my head.
簡單的幾行程序代碼
A few simple lines of computer code
就可以破解任何系統
that can break into any system.
我對那些客戶說  最後一名是膽小鬼
Told all my clients, last one to Sherlock is a sissy.
但現在我都知道了  我能用這個修改記錄
But now that it's up here, I can use it to alter all the records.
我能抹殺理查·布魯克  弄回金·莫堥蒂
I can kill Rich Brook and bring back Jim Moriarty.
不不不  這也太簡單了
No, no, no, no, no. This is too easy.
太簡單了
This is too easy.
根本就沒什麼代碼  笨蛋
There is no key, doofus!
那些數字毫無意義  一點意義都沒有
Those digits are meaningless. They're utterly meaningless.
你不會真以為幾行程序代碼
You don't really think a couple of lines of computer code
就能破解全世界的系統嗎
are going to crash the world around our ears?
我好失望哦  普通人夏洛克
I'm disappointed in you, ordinary Sherlock.
- 但那個節奏  - 是巴赫的1號協奏曲  謝謝
- But the rhythm... Partita no 1! Thank you, Johann Sebastian Bach.
- 那你又是怎麼...  - 怎麼黑進銀行
- But then how did you... ? - How did I break into the bank,
倫敦塔  還有監獄嗎
to the Tower, to the prison?
光天化日下的搶劫  只要有同夥就行啦
Daylight robbery! All it takes is some willing participants.
好戲開始了哦
我知道你會上鉤  這是你的弱點
I knew you'd fall for it. That's your weakness.
你總是把事情想得很聰明
You always want everything to be clever.
我們的遊戲能結束了嗎  最後一幕
Shall we finish the game? One final act.
幸好你選了一棟高樓  那樣做效果很好
Glad you chose a tall building. Nice way to do it.
做  做什麼
Do it? Do what?
是啊  當然了
Yes, of course.
自殺
My suicide.
天才偵探是個騙子
Genius detective proved to be a fraud.
我在報紙上看到  肯定是真的
I read it in the paper so it must be true.
我最愛報紙了
I love newspapers.
還有童話故事
Fairy tales.
尤其喜歡黑暗的童話
And pretty grim ones too.
天啊  約翰  你嚇死我了  警察那邊沒事吧
God, John, you made me jump. Is everything OK with the police?
夏洛克都解決了吧
Has Sherlock sorted it all out?
我的天
My God.
出租車
Taxi!
出租車  等等  我是警察  算是吧
Taxi! No, no, no. Police... sort of!
謝了  夥計  太謝謝了
Thanks, mate. Thanks a lot!
我能證明你偽造了那個假身份
I can prove that you created an entirely false identity.
你就自殺吧  那樣省力多了
Just kill yourself. It's a lot less effort.
跳啊
Go on.
為了我
For me.
好不好啦
Please!
你瘋了
You're insane.
你剛剛知道嗎
You're just getting that now? Wo- wo- wo!
好吧
Ok.
我再給你點動力
Let me give you a little extra incentive.
要是你不跳  你朋友就會死
Your friends will die if you don't.
- 約翰  - 不止是約翰  還有
- John? - Not just John. Everyone.
- 赫德森太太  - 還有
- Mrs Hudson? - Everyone.
- 雷斯垂德  - 三發子彈  三個殺手  三個死者
- Lestrade? - Three bullets, three gunmen, three victims.
沒有人能阻止他們了
There's no stopping them now...
除非他們看到你跳樓
unless my people see you jump.
儘管逮捕我  折磨我好了
You can have me arrested, you can torture me,
你想拿我怎麼樣隨便你
you can do anything you like with me,
但沒什麼能阻止他們扣下扳機
but nothing's going to prevent them from pulling the trigger.
你在這世上唯一的三個朋友死定了
Your only three friends in the world will die unless...
- 除非  - 我自殺  成就你的故事
- Unless... - I kill myself and complete your story.
你得承認  這樣更吸引人
You've got to admit, that's sexier.
- 我聲名狼藉地死去  - 當然了  這才是重點
- And I die in disgrace. - Of course. That's the point of this.
你現在有觀眾了哦
You've got an audience now.
請吧
Off you pop.
跳吧
Go on.
我告訴過你故事的結局
I told you how this ends.
只有你死
Your death is the only thing
殺手才會收手
that's going to call off the killers.
我肯定不會這麼做
I'm certainly not going to do it.
你能給我點時間嗎
Would you give me one moment, please?
讓我一個人待會
One moment of privacy.
拜託了
Please.
當然可以
Of course.
什麼
What?!
你笑什麼
What is it?
你知道了什麼
What did I miss?
你不會這麼做
You're not going to do it.
所以還有辦法讓殺手收手
So the killers can be called off,
有個代碼  暗號或數字
then there's a recall code or a word or a number.
如果我有你
I don't have to die
我就不用死
if I've got you.
你覺得你能讓我下令讓他們住手嗎
You think you can make me stop the order?
- 你覺得你能做到嗎  - 當然
- You think you can make me do that? - Yes.
- 你也這麼覺得  - 夏洛克  你哥哥和整個政府的人
- So do you. - Sherlock, your big brother and all the King's horses
都不能逼我做我不想做的事
couldn't make me do a thing I didn't want to.
是的  但我不是我哥哥  記得嗎
Yes, but I'm not my brother, remember?
我是你
I am you.
準備好做任何事
Prepared to do anything.
準備好毀滅一切
Prepared to burn.
準備好做普通人做不到的事
Prepared to do what ordinary people won't do.
你想和我在地獄堿菬ㄥ
You want me to shake hands with you in hell?
那我奉陪
I shall not disappoint you.
不
Nah.
你這話說大了
You talk big.
才不是呢
Nah.
你是普通人
You're ordinary.
你是普通人  你站在正義那一方
You're ordinary. You're on the side of the angels.
我也許是站在正義那一方
I may be on the side of the angels,
但這絕不代表我和他們是一種人
but don't think for one second that I am one of them.
對
No...
你不是
you're not.
我懂了
I see.
你不是普通人
You're not ordinary.
不是
No.
你是我
You're me.
你就是我
謝謝
Thank you...
夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
謝謝你了
Thank you.
上帝保佑你
Bless you.
只要我還活著
As long as I'm alive,
你就能救你的朋友  你就會有退路
you can save your friends, you've got a way out.
那就祝你好運了
Well, good luck with that.
不
No.
是的  先生  謝謝  再見
Yes, sir. Thank you. Bye.
喂
Hello?
- 約翰  - 夏洛克  你沒事吧
- John. - Hey, Sherlock. Are you OK?
轉過身  往回走  我這就來
Turn around and walk back the way you came. I'm coming in.
照我說的做
Just do as I ask!
求你了
Please.
在哪
Where?
停在那別動
Stop there.
- 夏洛克  - 好了  抬頭  我在屋頂上
- Sherlock? - OK, look up. I'm on the rooftop.
天啊
God.
我不能下來  所以我們只能這麼說話了
I... I can't come down, so we'll just have to do it like this.
怎麼了
What's going on?
我要道歉
An apology.
這一切都是真的
It's all true.
什麼
What?
他們說的關於我的一切  我創造了莫堥蒂
Everything they said about me. I invented Moriarty.
你為什麼要這麼說
Why are you saying this?
我是個冒牌貨
I'm a fake.
- 夏洛克  - 報紙上寫的都是真的
- Sherlock... - The newspapers were right all along.
我要你告訴雷斯垂德
I want you to tell Lestrade,
告訴赫德森太太和茉莉
I want you to tell Mrs Hudson and Molly.
告訴所有相信你的人
In fact, tell anyone who will listen to you...
我為了自己創造了莫堥蒂
that I created Moriarty for my own purposes.
好了  閉嘴  夏洛克  別說了
OK, shut up Sherlock. Shut up.
我們第一次見面的時候
The first time we met... the first time we met,
- 你就對我姐姐的事瞭如指掌吧  - 沒人能這麼聰明
- you knew all about my sister, right? - Nobody could be that clever.
你就可以
You could.
我調查了你
I researched you.
我們見面之前  我查了所有關於你的資料
Before we met, I discovered everything that I could
就為了讓你印象深刻
to impress you.
這只是個把戲罷了
It's a trick. Just a magic trick.
不  快別說了
No. All right, stop it now.
不  站在那別動
No. Stay exactly where you are.
- 別動  - 好吧
- Don't move. - All right.
好好看著我
Keep your eyes fixed on me.
- 求你了  你能為我做這件事嗎  - 什麼事
- Please, will you do this for me? - Do what?
這通電話
This phone call, it's...
是我的遺言
it's my note.
人們都會這麼做的吧
It's what people do, don't they?
留遺言
Leave a note?
留什麼鬼遺言啊
Leave a note when?
- 再見  約翰  - 不  不要
- Goodbye, John. - No. Don't...
夏洛克
Sherlock!
Sherlock.
夏洛克
Sherlock... Sherlock.
我是醫生  讓我過去  快讓我過去
I'm a doctor, let me come through. Let me come through, please.
他是我朋友  是我朋友  求求你們
He's my friend. He's my friend... Please.
求你們了  讓我...
Please, let me just...
上帝啊
Jesus!
不
No.
這不是真的
God, no.
冒牌天才自殺
你有什麼想說
There's stuff that you wanted to say...
- 卻沒有說的話  - 嗯
- but didn't say it. - Yeah.
現在說出來吧
Say it now.
對不起  我做不到
Sorry, I can't.
所有那些東西  那些科學儀器
There's all the stuff. All the science equipment.
我都裝在盒子堣F  不知道該怎麼辦
I left it all in boxes. I don't know what needs doing.
我覺得還是捐給學校吧
I thought I'd take it to a school.
你要不要...
Would you...?
我現在暫時沒法回去  我要緩一緩
I can't go back to the flat again, not at the moment.
我好生氣
I'm angry.
沒事的  約翰  這沒什麼奇怪
It's OK, John. There's nothing unusual in that.
他讓每個人都生氣
That's the way he made everyone feel.
夏洛克·福爾摩斯
看他在我桌子上留下的記號  還有那些噪音
All the marks on my table and the noise,
- 在凌晨一點半開槍  - 是啊
- firing guns at half past one in the morning... - Yeah.
還把該死的標本放在我冰箱
Bloody specimens in my fridge.
- 你怎麼能在放吃的地方放屍體  - 是啊
- Imagine, keeping bodies where there's food. - Yes.
還打架  還把牆壁弄得亂七八糟
And the fighting! Drove me up the wall with all his carryings- on.
聽著  我其實沒有這麼生氣  好嗎
Listen, I'm not actually that angry, OK?
好吧  我讓你一個人待會
OK. I'll leave you alone to, you know...
你曾經對我說過
You... you told me once...
你不是個英雄
that you weren't a hero.
我也曾一度以為你不是人
There were times I didn't even think you were human,
但我要對你說  你是...
but let me tell you this, you were...
我認識的...
the best man...
最出色...最有人情味的人
the most human... human being that I've ever known
沒有人能讓我相信  你對我說的這一切都是在騙我
and no- one will ever convince me that you told me a lie, so...
就這樣
there.
我好孤單
I was so alone...
我欠你好多
and I owe you so much.
但是  求你了  再求你一件事  就一件事
But, please, there's just one more thing, one more thing,
就一個奇跡  夏洛克  為了我  求你不要...
one more miracle, Sherlock, for me, don't be...
不要死
dead.
可以嗎  就當是為了我
Would you do that just for me?
別這樣  不要這麼對我
Just stop it. Stop this.
新福爾摩斯 第2季 第3集
Sherlock S02E03 720p hdtv x264
YYeTs人人影視